The next type of insert statement inserts
values into a table and does not involve using
a SELECT statement.
To execute such an insert statement, we need
to know the table we are inserting data into,
the columns that will receive data, and the
data itself.
Here, I have an INSERT statement that shows
that we will insert some data into the BikeRepairs
table.
The statement starts with the INSERT INTO
keywords and the table we are inserting data
into: BikeRepairs.
Then in parentheses, we see the columns that
will receive data.
Keep in mind that required fields must be
included here.
The VALUES keyword is next, followed by the
values we will add, making sure each value
corresponds with each column listed above.
For this example, I am inserting two repairs
into the table.
In real-life apps, code that pulls values
from form fields is a far more likely scenario
than for this example of hard-coded values.
Still, the goal is to see how an INSERT statement
is formed and executed.
I will execute this statement, and we have
two rows added to the BikeRepairs table.